# Simone Green

New York, NY | 917-783-8408 | e.simonegreen@gmail.com | GitHub | Portfolio | LinkedIn

### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

I am a creative and driven software engineer with a passion for entrepreneurship. My previous experience as an account executive has allotted me the opportunity to collaborate with different teams and manage client accounts. I'm experienced in leading cross-functional teams, overseeing project management, and building relationships with clients and partners.

### **SKILLS**

- Programming Languages: JavaScript, React.js, Vanilla Javascript, JQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Python, Express, Node.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, Git, GitHub
- Frameworks & Methodologies: Front-end Development, Back-end Development, ERDs, MVC Architecture, Authentication RESTful-Routing, Wireframing, Debugging
- **Software:** Microsoft Office suite, Photoshop, Google suite, SkyPad, SAP, PLM, IBT, SharePoint, NuOrder, Klayvio, Monday.com, Clikcup, Canva & Miro

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEERING PROJECTS

# Rubber Browser Game | GitHub

Remote, 09/2023

- Designed and developed a browser-based game from concept to completion, including game mechanics, user interface, and interactive gameplay elements
- Utilized HTML5, CSS, and JavaScript to create a responsive and visually appealing game interface

## Full-Stack CRUD App | GitHub

Remote, 10/2023

- Developed BeautyBook Discussions, fostering a vibrant hub for beauty enthusiasts to unite, driven by a mutual passion for sharing beauty insights. Aimed to cultivate a nurturing community of empowered women encouraging one another
- Implemented full-stack CRUD applications harnessing front-end technologies such as HTML5, CSS, and JavaScript frameworks alongside back-end technologies like Express, Node is, MongoDB, MongooseJS, and OAuth Authentication

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **General Assembly, Software Engineering Immersive**

Remote, 09/2023 - 12/2023

- Successfully completed 500+ hours of expert-led instruction in Software Engineering
- Built full-stack web applications utilizing Javascript, React, Express, Node.js, Python, Django, SQL, MongoDB, HTML5, & CSS3.
- Participated in team-driven projects, collaborating with developers to construct scalable applications.

#### NBK Consulting, Freelance Business Consultant & Brand Manager

New York, NY, 11/2021 - 07/2023

- Created and implemented messaging frameworks for marketing campaigns for 5 businesses, resulting in a 30% increase in brand awareness and engagement
- Conducted market research and competitive analysis to optimize messaging for a client's social media campaigns, resulting in a 25% growth in online sales
- Oversaw content creation for seasonal initiatives, product launches, and promotions while contracting and managing a high-performing team

### Revman International, Jr. Account Executive

New York, NY, 03/2019 - 02/2021

- Managed and maintained relationships with key stakeholders at Home Goods, TKX Europe, and Marshalls, resulting in a 20% increase in customer satisfaction scores
- Developed and executed sales strategies for soft home products, resulting in a 15% increase in revenue for 3rd tier accounts
- Collaborated with brand managers, product development, and designers to develop brand presentations and design forecasts

## Tory Burch, Handbags & Accessories Associate Account Executive

New York, NY, 10/2018 - 03/2019

Milan, Italy, Certificate: 07/2018

Certificate: 12/2023

Certificate: 07/2021

- Generated detailed reports on weekly selling performance for Neiman Marcus and Shopbop accounts, providing valuable insights to Sales Manager and contributing to a 10% increase in revenue
- Created order templates for confirmed orders and bulks/contracts
- Managed shipping logistics for all handbags and accessories orders, ensuring timely delivery and customer satisfaction, resulting in a 98% on-time delivery rate

## **EDUCATION**

General Assembly, Software Engineering Immersive

Brunchwork, Business Intensive

Nuova Accademia Di Belle Arti (NABA),

Summer Continuing Education Course: Fashion Marketing & Communications

# State University of New York at Oneonta,

BS: Fashion Textiles, Concentration Advertising & Marketing Communication Oneonta, NY, Graduated: 05/2015